哈里斯太太去巴黎
看着点儿！
Watch it!
是什么呢 艾迪？好消息坏消息？
What's it to be, Eddie? Good news or bad?
-早啊 钱德勒  -早上好 哈里斯太太
-Morning, Chandler. -Good morning, Mrs. Harris.
-你好吗？  -今天是我的幸运日
-How are you? -It's my lucky day today.
那不是跟每天一样
Same as every day.
-谢谢  -没事
-Thank you. -All right.
这儿怎么没人坐啊？
Why's no one took that seat?
或许我是留给你的呢
Maybe I saving it for you.
还不赶紧挪过去
Shove over, then.
说不出来你都不信 薇 发生了特别奇怪的事儿
You won't believe this, Vi. The strangest thing's just happened.
我觉得是种预兆
I reckon it's a sign.
艾达·哈里斯 你家男人怎么就
Harris, why that man of yours
不能跟别人一样寄信呢？
can't use the post like everybody else?
我家艾迪不怎么擅长写字
Not much of a writer, my Eddie.
喔 好冷
Ooh! So cold.
-有车来吗？  -没
-Anyone coming? -No.
伦敦  1957年
早 纽康比先生 这么早就起来了
Oh, morning, Mr. Newcombe. Up bright and early.
职责所在啊 哈里斯太太 这是我侄女 波西亚
Duty calls, Mrs. Harris. Uh, my niece, Portia.
非常荣幸
Oh, delighted, I'm sure.
彭罗斯小姐
Ooh-ooh, Miss Penrose.
这是被轰炸了啊
Bombs away.
你也太早了吧？
Aren't you awfully early?
都一点半了 亲爱的
It's gone half past- 00, dear.
不是吧
No.
天啊 我要试镜
Christ, my bloody audition.
我没衣服穿
Oh, I haven't a thing to wear.
你穿什么都好看 亲爱的
Oh, you look lovely in anything, dear.
你看
There.
这套怎么样？
What about this?
你弄哪儿去了我的... 剧本？
Oh, what have you done with my... script?
-慢着 慢着 等一下  -老天啊
-Oh, hang on, hang on. Hang on. -Oh, for God's sake.
好了 好运哟 亲爱的
There. Good luck, sweetheart.
谢谢 亲爱的 你就是天使
Thanks, darling. You're an angel.
没有你我可怎么办？
What would I do without you?
我们来开心一下
Let's enjoy ourselves!
这不是非凡的H太太和她可靠的伙伴嘛
Well, if it isn't the marvelous Mrs. H and her trusty sidekick.
两位女士喝点什么？这星期很走运
What can I get you, ladies? It's been a lucky week.
两杯波特加柠檬
Two port and lemon.
你要是庄家 那每礼拜都走运啊
Every week's lucky if you're the bookmaker.
你说得没错 亲爱的 两杯波特加柠檬谢谢
You're not wrong there, love. Two port and lemon, please.
当然 现在我有了你们的陪伴 就什么都不缺了
Course, now I've got your company, I'm in clover.
你以为一杯酒就能让我们陪你吗 阿奇先生？
You think you get our company for one drink, Mr. Archie?
这俩可是很会看人的
Now, these two are a proper judge of character.
它们喜欢你 艾达·哈里斯
They like you, Harris.
它们要是这么从没 干嘛跟着你啊？
Why they stick with you, if they're so smart?
你又为何跟着她 她这臭脾气？
Why do you stick with her, her so crabby?
我第一次造飞机的时候 认识了她
Met her me first shift building planes.
从没遇到过更好的朋友
Never had a better friend.
这个人的毛病就是 总是说实话
Trouble with this one, she always speak the truth.
管不住自己
Can't help herself.
这可是相当痛苦的
That is a terrible affliction.
好了 乖乖地 女士们
All right, behave yourself, ladies.
我会盯着你们的
I'll be watching you.
战争结束很久了
War's been over a long time.
你家艾迪永远不会回来了
Your Eddie's never coming back.
拆开吧
Go on.
好
Yeah.
"亲爱的 哈里斯太太
"Dear Mrs. Harris,
"随函附上爱德华·哈里斯中士的私人物品
"Please find enclosed the personal effects of Sergeant Edward Harris,
"是在波兰华沙一处坠机现场找回的
"recovered from a crash site near Warsaw, Poland.
"由于这一发现
"As a result of this discovery,
"哈里斯中士现被宣布...
"Sergeant Harris is now posted...
"于1944年3月2日
"killed in action,
"在行动中牺牲
"2 March 1944.
"请等待英国皇家空军中央管理部门的进一步联系"
"Please await further communication from RAF Central Administration."
艾达
Oh, Ada.
我很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
我早该想到他...
I-I should've known he...
如果他可以 一定会回到我身边的 对吧
He would've got back to me if he could've, you know...
无论如何
one way or another.
好了
Well...
那就这样了
that's that, then.
无拘无束 自由自在
Footloose and fancy-free.
好了 亲爱的
All right, love.
我希望你没受罪
I hope it was quick.
想你
Miss you.
不 当然是晚上
No, the evening do, absolutely,
不是婚礼早餐
but not the wedding breakfast.
那个 那个...
Uh, you know, Mrs....
哈里斯太太 麻烦你 你能...
Mrs. Harris, excuse me. Could you just...
那个给你
just take that...
不 这是敲诈
No, that is extortion.
你必须回去跟他们解释 我们不可能负担得起
You must go back and explain to them that we can't possibly afford that.
当然必须是香槟
Well, of course it must be champagne.
我...我...提醒他们查尔斯是他们的议员
I-I-I... Remind them that Charles is their MP.
这肯定得算什么吧 哈？是啊
That must be worth something, huh? Yes.
拜拜
Toodle-pip.
这婚礼简直是我的葬礼
This wedding's going to be the death of me.
你有孩子吗 哈里斯太太？
Do you have children, Mrs. Harris?
从头到尾 就是一场噩梦
A nightmare of expense from start to finish.
是啊
Oh, yes.
可怜的老海军上将丹特 不得不做出最后的牺牲
Poor old Admiral Dant had to make the ultimate sacrifice.
启航前往佳士得和更温暖的海岸
Setting sail for Christie's and balmier shores.
怎么看都是个可怕的男人
Dreadful man, by all accounts.
说到这个 丹特夫人
Talking of accounts, Lady Dant,
不知道你能否结一下...
I was wondering if you might be able to sett...
我们一直是勒紧裤腰带过日子
We've been tightening our belts for so long now,
还能喘气儿 真是奇迹了
it's a miracle we can all still breathe.
很美吧？
Isn't it divine?
我发过誓 再也不踏进蒙田大道
I swore I would never set foot in the Avenue Montaigne,
可是要办婚礼 又是"去了巴黎"就
but what with the wedding and "when in Paris" and...
我一眼看到这件拉维桑特...
The moment I laid eyes on Ravissante...
-拉维桑特  -我就被迷住了
-Ravissante. -...I was ravished.
要500镑
To the tune of 500 pounds.
-500镑买一条裙子?  -嘘嘘嘘 别让丹特勋爵听到
-500 quid for a dress? -Shh, shh, shh. Lord Dant.
我不介意承认最近各种事情是有点迟了 但是...
I don't mind admitting things have been a bit bloody of late, but...
我一穿上
when I put it on...
其他就都不重要了
...nothing else matters.
-洛蒂？  -快 藏起来
-Lotte? -Now, quickly, hide it away.
千万不能让爵爷看到 等我先给他做做工作的
His Lordship must not see it until I've had time to work on him.
拉维桑特
Ravissante.
克里斯汀·迪奥
By Christian Dior.
晚安 亲爱的
Night, love.
南伦敦邮报！
South London Post!
周六赛果 所有足球赛的结果
Saturday results! All your football results.
南伦敦邮报！
South London Post!
-抱歉  -周六赛果
-Sorry. -Saturday results!
所有足球赛的结果
All your football results.
南伦敦邮报！周六赛果
South London Post! Saturday results!
曼联 两球
ANNOUNCER Manchester United two,
黑池 两球
Blackpool two.
纽卡斯尔 五球
Newcastle five,
利物浦 三球
Liverpool three.
普雷斯顿 两球
Preston North End two,
朴次e斯 两球
Portsmouth two.
现在回到其他方面的体育报道
And now we return to the rest of the sports report.
不 不！
No! No!
是我的艾迪
Oh, it's my Eddie.
我的天使
It's my angel.
你跟我装傻呢 女人
You gone simple on me, woman?
我赢了 薇
I won, Vi.
我赢了
I've won.
你可对她好点儿 她刚赢了足彩
You want to make nice to her. She's only gone and won the pools.
艾达 你打算怎么做？
Ada, what you going to do?
我要买一条裙子
I'm going to buy a dress.
参加军团舞会的漂亮衣服
Something pretty for the Legion Dance.
没错
Yeah.
来自巴黎的 一条克里斯汀·迪奥的裙子
A Christian Dior dress from Paris.
500镑
500 quid.
你赢了多少啊？
How much you win?
迪奥裙子 目标金额 500磅
彩票中奖 -150
凯蒂 -3先令 6便士
还有车票吗？
Any more tickets, please?
去哪里 女士？
Where to, ma'am?
独自一人 薇奥莱特小姐？
Single, Miss Violet?
嗯哼 没有男人就不用我跟在屁股后面收拾
Mm-hmm. No cleaning up after no man for me.
早上好 纽康比先生
Morning, Mr. Newcombe.
哈里斯太太 我...
Mrs. Harris, I, uh...
你好像没见过我侄女 萨曼莎
I don't believe you've met my niece, Samantha.
没有呢 还没有这个荣幸
Oh, no, I haven't had the pleasure.
纽康比先生
Um, Mr. Newcombe.
如果你知道有谁需要我的服务
If you know of anyone who could use me services-um...
或许是你哪位侄女？
one of your nieces, perhaps?
萨曼莎 H太太十分谨慎小小心
Samantha, Mrs. H is the soul of discretion.
若不是我的门把手光亮如新 别人都不知道她去过
One would never know she'd been but for the polish on my knobs.
噢 贾尔斯
Oh, Giles.
谢谢
Thank you.
隐形织补
艾达·哈里斯太太
邮局存款 78英镑 7先令 9便士
选拔的事 我很遗憾 亲爱的
Sorry about the audition, love.
都不知道我费个什么劲
Oh, I don't know why I bother.
"太年轻" "太老"
"Too young." "Too old."
"太高" "太胖"
"Too tall." "Too fat."
你正好 亲爱的
You're just right, ducks.
我二十...三岁
I'm twenty... three.
再过两年 就彻底没戏了
Couple more years, and it's all over for me.
你还有大把时间呢
Oh, you've plenty of time.
你根本想象不到 哈里斯太太
You can't imagine what it's like, Mrs. Harris,
总是担心自己的外表
always having to worry about your looks.
嘿 灰姑娘 你带破布来干什么？
Hey, Cinderella, why'd you bring them rags?
我要去参加舞会...等我买了裙子
I will go to the ball... when I get me dress.
噢"阿"大麻烦来了
Oh, here comes trouble with a capital "A."
你好 阿奇
Hello, Archie.
艾达 正是我要找的姑娘
Ada, the very girl I was after.
-有什么事 亲爱的？  -别让我太激动啊
-What can I do for you, ducks? -Now, don't get me excited.
-你知道我心脏受不了  -拉倒吧你
-You know I've got a dodgy ticker. -Oh, get away with you.
-她有比你更重要的安排  -看得出来
-She got bigger plans than you. -I can see that.
你介意帮我个忙 照看一下春天和夏天吗？
So, would you mind doing me a favor and look after Spring and Summer?
因为辛西娅实在和狗相处不来
Because Cynthia there's not exactly a dog's best friend.
来吧
Go on.
谢谢
Thank you.
你真是个大救星
You are an absolute star.
你还行
And you're all right.
C? 好 我们来吧
C? All right, here we go.
尾巴摇起来 宝贝
Shake that tail, baby.
这就是我们 薇
That's what we are, Vi.
-隐形女人  -那是你
-The invisible women. -Speak for yourself.
姐姐要出场了
They see me coming. Mm!
不好意思 夫人
Beg your pardon, milady.
夫人 我的薪水
Milady, um, my account.
不知道能否给我结一下
I was wondering if you might settle up.
很抱歉 哈里斯天天
Oh, I'm so sorry, Mrs. Harris.
恐怕我忘记去银行了
I'm afraid I forgot to pop to the bank.
这场婚礼真是噩梦 每个人都说要来
This wedding is a nightmare. Everybody has said yes.
你不介意等到下周吧？
you wouldn't mind waiting until next week, would you?
问题是 有点急 因为我
Well, uh, the thing is, it's become a bit pressing because I need to...
噢 都这个时间了？
Oh, is that the time?
其实吧 哈里斯太太
Actually, Mrs. Harris,
恐怕我不得不给你减时了
I'm afraid I'm going to have to reduce your hours.
减时？不要啊 夫人 拜托...
Reduce? N-No, please. Milady, please...
如今我们都得节约 不是吗
Well, we all have to economize these days, don't we?
抱歉了
Sorry.
我知道你在 女人 坐在黑暗冰冷中
I know you're there, woman, in the dark and cold.
我没事 薇
I'm all right, Vi.
阿奇可以免费带我们去白城
Archie has got us free into White City.
不行 我有好多要缝补的
Oh, no, I've got all this mending.
不 不行 我不去 薇 薇
N-No. No, no, Vi. Vi...
我们开心一下
Have us a bit of fun.
6 高级时装
上帝啊 你看 这是个暗示
Oh, good Lord. Look. It's a sign.
-你有好内幕？  -是的！
-You got a good tip? -Yeah!
是的 我有！
Yeah, I have!
-借...借...借过一下  -嘿
-Um... excu... excuse... -Hey.
艾达 你想小赌一把？
Ada, you fancy a flutter?
-是的  -赌什么
-Yeah. -What'll it be?
100镑 押6号
100 quid on number six.
赢
To win.
这么多？
A ton?
老天啊 艾达 不行 收起来
For the love of Mike, Ada, no, put it away.
不 6号
No. Number six.
-高级时装 谢谢  -那条狗就剩一把骨头了
-Haute Couture, please. -The dog's a bag of bones.
就是插了火箭都赢不了
It couldn't win with a rocket up its arse.
你快说说她 阿奇 她疯了
You tell her, Archie. She's lost her marbles.
不 就要"高级时装"
No, it's Haute Couture.
这就是暗示 不然还能是什么呢
It's a sign. How could it be anything else?
艾达 姐们儿 我做这行很久了 好吗？
Ada, girl, I've been doing this a long time, all right?
-暗示赢不了比赛  -在今晚之前 是没有
-Signs don't win races. -Not till tonight, they didn't.
我钱都准备好了
My money's good.
数数看 拜托
Count it, please.
好
Yeah.
这儿
Here.
就这儿 很好
Here we go. That's good.
这位置不错 好
Oh, we got a good spot. Right.
祝我好运
Oh. Wish me luck.
-艾达  -加油啊 高级时装
-Oh, Ada. -Come on, Haute Couture.
看啊 她在最前面
Oh, look, she's in the lead!
冲啊！
Come on!
在前面
It's in front.
加油啊
Come on!
分别是 机灵伯爵
It's Clever Count,
蓝色条纹 和暴风海湾
Blue Streak, and Stormy Bay.
你们看"高级时装"
And would you look at that-Haute Couture has just
突然醒来 知道自己是来干吗的了
woken up and remembered what she's here for.
好吧 向你致敬 姐们儿
Well... Hats off to you, girl.
你冲了一把
You went for it.
我去找个圣约翰救护队 他们可能有白兰地
I'll go find a St John's Ambulance. They might have a tot of brandy.
我喝
For me.
你是对的 薇 那么多钱
You were right, Vi-all that money.
我的艾迪会以我为耻的
My Eddie'd be ashamed of me.
我去去就来 好吗
I'll be right back, huh?
做梦 没有错 艾达
Nothing wrong with dreaming, Ada, hmm?
我来伦敦那会儿 满大街都是我的梦想
When I came to London, the streets were paved with my dreams.
你就是这样的人 一个梦想家
That's what you are. You're a dreamer.
都写在你的脸上呢
Plain as the nose on your face.
消停会儿吧 薇 我没事
Give over, Vi. I'm all right.
哈里斯太太？
Mrs. Harris?
爱德华·哈里斯太太？是你丈夫的事
Mrs. Edward Harris? It's about your husband.
请坐吧
Sit down, please.
哈里斯中士是直到4月19日才被宣布
Sergeant Harris wasn't declared missing in action
在行动中失踪的
until April the 19th.
是 我在那时候接到了电报
Uh, yeah, that's when I got the telegram.
他生日的转天
It's a day after his birthday.
是 我们现在了解到
Ah, yes. Well, um, as we now know,
波罗利马326飞机 是在1944年3月2日坠机的
Flight Polo Lima 326 crashed on March the 2nd, 1944,
也就是说 哈里斯中士死后
meaning that Sergeant Harris was paid
还领了将近7周的工资
for almost seven weeks after his death.
每天6先令
At, um, six shillings a day.
你来就是告诉我这个？
Is that what you come to tell me?
过了这么久
After all this time.
我的艾迪还欠你们钱？
That my Eddie owes you back pay?
他这辈子一毛钱都没有过
When he never owed a penny in his life.
他为了国王和国家献出了生命
When he give up his life for king and country.
你可真好意思 来我家 喝我的茶
You got a nerve. Coming into my home, drinking my tea,
抹黑他的名声
blackening his name.
你要多少钱？
How much do you want?
多少？然后你就可以走了
How much? And then you can leave.
我想...你误会了
I-I think you've got the wrong end of the stick.
是吗？
Oh, have I? Well, I'll tell you
那我告诉你 你要是不当心的话
where you can shove your stick in a minute,
-等下你可以滚了  -天啊 不是的 我...
-if you don't watch out. -Oh, golly, no. Um, I, uh...
我是来给你钱的 哈里斯太太
I'm here to give you money, Mrs. Harris,
-不是来找你要钱  -我受够了...
-not-not to take it from you. -I've had enough of...
-你说什么？  -是的 没错
-What'd you say? -Y-Yes. Righto.
你应该从1944年开始 领取战争遗孀抚恤金
Uh, you should have been receiving a-a war widow's pension since 1944.
即便扣除那一点 也是很可观的一笔钱
It comes to quite a tidy sum, uh, with that small deduction.
只要你还没有再婚
So long as you haven't remarried.
噢 拉倒吧
Oh, give over.
他可能随时回来 我就像个傻子
He might have come back any minute, I'd have looked a right Charlie.
好吧...
well...
我想你最好坐下吧
I suppose you'd better sit down.
-还是得把茶喝了  -不加奶
-Have that cup of tea after all. -Um, no milk.
她这辈子没做过一件错事 长官
She's never done a thing wrong her whole life, sir.
她有点痴迷一条裙子 但现在没事儿了
She went a bit crazy on account of some dress, but she's fine now.
不需要担心
Nothing to worry about.
-你好  -哈里斯太太？
-Oh, hello. -Mrs. Harris?
你来告诉我 皇冠珠宝归我了？
You come to tell me I got the crown jewels?
她脑子还是不太正常
She's still not right in the head.
差不多 你上交的那枚钻石胸针
Almost. That diamond clip you handed in--
失主想要奖励你这位诚实的好市民
the owner wants to give you a reward for being an honest citizen.
她就是呢 长官 对错误都很诚实
Oh! She is, sir, honest to a fault.
-进来喝杯茶吧  -那我就不客气了 谢谢
-Come in and have a cup of tea. -Don't mind if I do. Thank you.
来吧 薇 我们可以来个茶话会
Oh, come on, Vi. We can have a knees-up.
喂 等等我
Oi, wait for me.
你或许要把香槟拿出来了
And, uh, you might want to break out the bubbly.
今天又是你的幸运日吗 阿奇
You having another lucky day, Archie?
事实上 还真是 你也是
As a matter of fact, I am, and so are you.
消息传得真快啊
News travels fast.
那个 你押在那只两条腿的狗身上的赌注
So, that bet you put on that two-legged dog...
是啊 不...不用担心
Oh, y-yeah, don't... don't worry about that.
我已经明白了
I've come to me senses.
不 老板当时在 所以我必须收钱
No, the boss was there, so I had to take the money,
但我偷摸藏了10镑
but I managed to hold back a tenner.
你不该那么做 阿奇
You shouldn't have done that, Archie.
你可能有麻烦的
You could have got into trouble.
没什么事吧 哈里斯太太？
All tickety-boo, Mrs. Harris?
抱歉 我不知道你有客人在
Oh, sorry, I didn't realize you had company.
你好 这是怎么了？
Hello. What's going on here?
老天爷啊
For the love of Mike.
-我回头再找你  -不 阿奇 阿奇
-Uh, I'll see you later. -Uh, no, Archie, Archie.
稍等我一下 好吗 有点私事
Uh, can you just give me a moment? It-it's personal.
-水烧开了？  -是啊
-That the kettle calling? -Ah, righto.
怎么了？出事了？
What's going on? Something up?
说来话长 你刚说什么？
It's a long story. What were you saying?
我拿了你点钱 上一场比赛押了铁定赢的
So, I took your money and put it on a sure thing in the last race.
然后呢
And, um...
你的赌注回来了 还多了一点
...your stake back and a wee bit more.
不 阿奇 我不能要
Oh, n-no, Archie, I couldn't.
-我...  -这是你的钱 拿着吧
-I... -It's your money. Take it.
我不能留着 女人
I can't keep it, woman.
里面的警员会没收我的执照的 拿着吧
PC Plod in there would have my license. Come on.
答应到时候要跟我跳支舞
Just promise me a dance at the Legion.
谢谢 阿奇
Thanks, Archie.
非常感谢
Much obliged.
天啊
Blimey.
战争遗孀赔偿金
钻石 赌狗
总金额 582英镑 7先令 3便士
飞起来了吗？
Are we flying?
非常抱歉 女士们先生们
We're terribly sorry, ladies and gentlemen.
有一台引擎似乎有些故障
There seems to be a fault with one engine.
维修可能会造成些许延误
There will be a slight delay while we try and fix the problem.
延误？
Delay?
多长时间？
How long?
我要一天之内来回呢
I've got to be there and back in a day.
天啊
Oh, God.
巴黎
Paris.
巴黎 勒布尔热机场
好 巴黎 我来了
Righto, Paris, here I come.
可真够远的
It's a fair old walk.
你好
bonjour.
英国人？
什么？
Beg your pardon?
一个英国女人
谢谢 嗯
Thank you. Yeah.
我是来买一条裙子的
Um, I'm here to buy a dress.
迪奥的
From Dior.
迪奥？
Dior?
是啊 我也是
Ah, oui.Me also.
远吗？迪奥？
Is it far-Dior?
20分钟
20 minutes.
但你要是喝了酒 那就俩钟头
Uh, but after you take wine, two hours.
我陪你走过去
I walk you there.
明早 好不？
Tomorrow morning, eh?
饿不？
不 不用 谢谢 我不能 不了
Oh, no, no, thanks. I couldn't, no.
好吧 那就来一口
All right, go on, then.
哎哟
Oh, blimey.
街上怎么这么多垃圾呢？
Why is all this rubbish on the streets?
大老板骗...
The big boss cheats...
-工人 明白？  -是 是
-The worker, yes? -Yeah, yeah.
不行 结束了
工人说"不干了"
The worker say, "No more."
他们受够了
-垃圾工人罢工了？  -对
-The binmen are on strike? -Ah, yes.
现在整个儿巴黎 闻起来...
Now all Paris, uh, smells, uh...
跟我一个味儿
...uh, like me.
好的 我们到了
迪奥公司
天啊
Oh, God.
祝你好运 英国女士
你是一个高贵的女人
You are a noble woman.
记住 在法国 工人是国王
And remember, in France, the worker is king.
尽可能拖住他们 她不会很久了 我肯定
娜塔莎小姐！
借过一下 女士
小姐！
Oh, miss!
笨手笨脚的丫头！
你没事吧 亲爱的？
You all right, love?
安德烈 怎么回事啊？差点儿伤到我
-你有受伤吗？  -没有 抱歉
-Did you hurt yourself? -No. Sorry.
谢谢
Thank you.
-你确定？  -是的
-Are you sure? -Yes.
小姐？
Miss?
小姐
Miss!
-您没事吧?  -别碰我!
严禁入内
不 小姐
No, miss.
喔 小姐！
Ooh-ooh! Miss!
小姐？给你这个
Miss? Here you go.
你又救了我一次 女士
Once again, you save me, madame.
抱歉 我太迟了
I'm sorry. I'm very late.
谢谢
Thank you.
没关系 只要你人好好的
It's all right. As long as you're in one piece.
当心 当心 当心
打扰一下 亲爱的
Oh. Excuse me, dear.
哪里可以找到连衣裙？
Where would I find the frocks?
恐怕你来错地方了 夫人
I fear you have the wrong address, madame.
-我叫人来带你去  -不用
-I will call someone to show you the way. -No. No, no.
抱歉 我...我...我想买一条裙子
Sorry. I'm-I'm... I'm after a frock.
一条500镑的
One of them 500-pound ones.
麻烦你在那边等一下 很快有人来接待你
Please, if you could wait over here, somebody will attend you directly.
啊 伯爵夫人
日安 蒂森豪森男爵夫人
你好 夫人
梅尔西埃夫人
请
等一下 请问
Now, hang on. Excuse me.
夫人 我...我先来的 比他们都早啊
Madame, I-I was here first, before any of this lot.
你们没听说过"排队"吗？
Ain't you heard of queuing?
阿瓦隆夫人 总是这么优雅
玛蒂尔达 都变样子了
打扰一下 抱歉
Excuse me. Look, I'm sorry.
-请  -我...我...我不想闹事儿
-Please. -I'm-I'm... I'm not one to make a fuss,
但在我们那儿 女店员是很愿意为人服务的
but where I come from, shopgirls are pleased to be of service.
女店员？
Shopgirls?
这个倒霉的家伙 怎么会进来的？
这个女人明显疯了
这位女士想买一条裙子
This lady wishes to buy a dress.
告诉她该去哪里买
Direct her to a suitable shop.
百货公司
快去
Go.
请让我送您出去吧
Uh, please let me escort you out.
不不不不 等一下
No, no, no, no, no, hang on a minute.
我大老远来的
I've come miles.
给人洗地板 干活儿
Saved every penny scrubbing floors
辛苦攒下的钱 就为了买这条连衣裙
and I don't know what so I can buy this frock.
克里斯汀迪奥的裙子 可不是便宜货
A Christian Dior gown is not for pennies.
马上把她弄走
Have her removed at once.
好吧
Right.
你要是认为我没钱
If you think I ain't got the money...
你看
there.
是真钱 科尔伯特夫人
要是谁都能这样...
你是迪奥先生吗？
Are you Mr. Dior?
噢 不是的 我是富维尔先生 会计
Oh, oh, no, I'm Mr. Fauvel, accounts.
让我帮你...
Let me help you with the...
今天 迪奥先生会发布他的计周年设计
不得有任何千扰
打扰一下 亲爱的夫人 但我很荣幸
Excuse me, chère madame, but it would be my honor
请你作为我的客人 欣赏设计
to have you view the collection as my guest.
收好
There you are.
谢谢
Merci.
请吧？
Shall we?
姑娘们 你们绝对不相信刚刚发生了什么
有个伦敦来的清洁大婶 想买一条裙子
-清洁大婶?   -对 买迪奥礼服!
她带着所有钱来的
科尔伯特夫人都不知所措了
娜塔莎 你一定要来看看她 她可太棒了
快来看 看啊！
夫人
到了
It's here.
谢谢
Thank you.
她把每一分钱都攒起来 过来看我们的！
就是她 坐在沙萨涅侯爵旁边的
看到没？
怎么回事？
回去工作！
赶紧地！
等看到你想要的裙子
When you see the dress you want,
你可以把号码写下来
you can write the number down here.
我在欣赏你的领花
Oh, I was just admiring your buttonhole.
这是露易斯欧迪
It's Louise Odier.
是的 很漂亮 很香
Yes, it's lovely. Proper scent.
你是一位玫瑰鉴赏家吗？
Are you a connoisseur of roses?
我丈夫艾迪在考文特花园工作过 花市
My husband Eddie worked at Covent Garden, the flower market.
他总是带一些零零碎碎的回家来
He was always bringing home odds and ends, you know.
玫瑰 是我最喜欢的
Roses are me favorite.
你是来为太太选礼服的吗？
You after a dress for your wife?
-幸运的女人  -我太太过世了
-Ooh. Lucky woman. -My wife is dead.
请原谅 先生
Oh, I do beg your pardon, sir.
我真是多嘴
My clumsy clogs.
我家艾迪也是
My Eddie and all.
不过是的 太太会和我一起来的
But yes, uh, my wife and I would come here together.
我喜欢欣赏美丽的衣裳
I like to see beautiful clothes.
当然 还有美丽的女人
And beautiful women, of course.
这怎么可能
又是她！
科尔伯特夫人？
这可不行
抱歉 阿瓦隆夫人
我们再找个更好的位置
不！这就是我们平时的位子
我们就先忍了这口气 但不能就这么算了
玛蒂尔达
喔 开始了
Oh, here we go.
1号
束腰套装
2号
瓦尔帕莱索
3号
神秘
真漂亮
Oh, that's lovely.
4号 科科特
42号 酒馆
用香槟色雪纺制成的晚礼服
你看啊
Oh, will you look.
卡拉卡斯
玫瑰人生
十四行诗
波多黎各
黑缎波点鸡尾酒礼服
噢 好美
Oh, that's lovely.
维纳斯
Vénus.
-这是几号？  -73
-What number's that? -73.
-维纳斯 对  -73号 维纳斯
-Vénus.Yes. -73. Vénus.
-这件是几号？  -89
-What number's that? -89.
诱惑
Temptation.
是啊
Oh, yeah.
精彩！
Bravo!
那人是谁啊？
Who's that bloke?
是大师本尊 迪奥先生
Well, that's the master himself, Monsieur Dior.
真假
Go on.
他长得像我的送奶工
He looks like my milkman.
好运 夫人
Well, good luck, madame.
希望你找到你想要的
I hope you find what you're looking for.
是啊
Oh, well...
送你
Here.
你不想收下吗？
You do not wish to keep it?
想 很美 谢谢你
Yeah, it's-it's lovely. Thank you.
很高兴
Enchanté.
不用管我
Don't mind me.
请问 夫人
Yes, madame?
-你选好了吗？  -是的 嗯...
-Have you made your selection? -Yes. Um...
-89号 谢谢 诱惑  -当然
-Number 89, please. Temptation. -Of course.
-请问你的名字  -哈里斯
-Your name, please. -Harris.
-艾达·哈里斯太太  -销售姑娘？
-Mrs. Harris. -Sales girl?
你知道我们的安排
很抱歉 夫人
My apologies, madame.
-失陪一下  -好
-Excusez-moi. -Oh, yeah.
好 阿瓦隆夫人 有什么可以帮你的？
我已经选好了
I've made my choice.
-太好了 阿瓦隆夫人  -诱惑 89号
哈里斯夫人 很遗憾...
Madame Harris, I regret...
"诱惑"可能有点麻烦
Well, there is a difficulty with Temptation.
阿瓦隆夫人要了
It seems Madame Avallon demands it.
那这怎么办？你们裙子就一件吗？
How's that work, then? You only got the one dress?
很抱歉 夫人坚持仅此一件
I'm sorry. Madame insists on exclusivity.
阿瓦隆夫人 是我们最忠实的客人之一
Madame Avallon is one of our most devoted clients.
她丈夫就是出名的"垃圾大王"
And her husband is known as "The King of Rubbish."
但是 如果你两手空空离开迪奥公馆
But we would be so sorry if you were to leave Maison Dior
我们也很遗憾
without a purchase.
你的卡片上还写了73号
And you also wrote number 73 on your card.
维纳斯
Vénus.
是啊 我没想到还能有更美的
Yeah, I never thought nothing could be more beautiful.
-直到我看到了"诱惑"  -非常好的选择 夫人
-Not till I saw Temptation. -An excellent choice, madame.
是啊 多少钱？
Yeah. How much is it?
"维纳斯"是60万法郎
Vénusis 600,000 francs.
430英镑
430 pounds.
包起来 我还要赶飞机
Wrap it up. I got a plane to catch.
-我已经迟到一天了  -这件裙子不能给你
-I'm a day late as it is. -Oh, you cannot have this gown.
别告诉我有人也要独占啊
Oh, don't tell me someone wants that exclusive and all.
但是 哈里斯夫人 每件裙子都是
Mais Madame Harris, every dress is made
为客人量身定做的
and fitted individually for the client.
是啊 这是高级时装
Yes, this is haute couture.
我们当然会原样重新制作"维纳斯"的
We will, of course, reproduce Vénusexactly as you saw it,
-但问题是...  -为我做一件？
-but the thing is... -Make me one?
需要多长时间？
How long's that gonna take?
起码要两周
Well, at least two weeks.
至少啊
Ooh. At least.
还要多次试穿
Several fittings are necessary.
什么 要离开两星期？
What, leave my people for a fortnight?
他们会换别人的 我就得去睡大马路了
They'd find someone else, and then I'd be out on the streets.
快 快 赶快去机场吧
Vite, vite, to the airport, then.
要是你错过飞机 我可无法原谅自己
I would not forgive myself if you missed your flight.
-什么 不带着我的礼服？  -打扰一下
-What, without my dress? -Excusez-moi.
或许你可以打电话给朋友？
Perhaps there is a friend you can call?
可以帮忙你的清洁工作
Someone who can assist you with your cleaning.
是有薇在 但她快被我搞得没有耐心了
Well, uh, there's Vi, but I've tried her patience enough as it is.
再说 她没电话
Anyway, she's not on the phone.
我们或许给她发封电报
Uh, we might send her a telegram.
对 对啊 没错
哈里斯太太 是有可能让
Uh, Mrs. Harris, uh, it might be possible to encourage
裁剪和缝纫工人加快速度的
the cutter and seamstress to work a little faster.
或许薇夫人可以帮你代班一个星期？
And Madame Vi could fill you in for one week, perhaps?
嗯...你真好心 但是不行
Well... you're kind, but I can't.
再说 我没地方住啊
Anyway, I got nowhere to stay.
我只能错过了
I'll have to give it a miss.
我姐姐出门了
My sister is away.
如果你...愿意接受
If you... would accept, um,
你可以去我家住 住我姐的房间
you could stay at my place, uh, in my sister's room.
你真是个天使啊 是不是
You're a proper angel, aren't you?
这是我的荣幸
It'll be my pleasure.
我们可以立马帮你量身
Um, we can have your measurements taken at once.
是不是 科尔伯特夫人？
N'est-ce pas, Madame Colbert?
工作室没事儿干
就专门服务这一个订单？
现金买卖 夫人 以我们目前的状况...
很好 富维尔先生 看来现在你可以做主了
来吧 哈里斯夫人 来
Come, Madame Harris. Come.
我们得赶快
We must be quick.
走啊你 别傻站着
-太棒了 夫人  -太棒了
-Bravo, madame. -Bravo.
请 夫人
Please, madame.
在伍尔沃斯买连衣裙可见不着这场面
You don't get all this hoo-ha when you buy a frock down Woolworths.
我也可以告诉你 在这儿 这种事不是每天发生的
Well, I can tell you such things do not happen every day here, either.
啊 这位女士要求她的裙子
Ah, the lady who must have her dress...
快 快 快
大衣 麻烦你
Your coat, please.
-还有开衫  -对 开衫
-Et le cardigan. -Yeah, me cardy.
非常感谢
Thank you very much.
十三
八十二
六十二
夫人的身材和模特一样
Madame has the proportions of a model.
铁路模型还差不多
Model railway, more like.
拐弯的地方
One of the curvy bits.
谢谢
Oh, thank you.
非常感谢
Thank you very much.
夫人？
Madame?
我送你？
May I give you a lift?
噢 如果不麻烦的话
Oh, well, if it's no bother.
不会
No.
我要去富维尔先生家
Uh, I'm going to Mr. Fauvel's.
18号 好的 很方便
The 18th, yes. That's easy.
抱歉车里有点乱
Oh, forgive the mess.
他是你朋友吗 富维尔先生？
Is he a friend of yours, Mr. Fauvel?
不 不是 富维尔先生只是给我开支票的人
No. No, I-I know Mr. Fauvel only as the hand that signs my check.
就是"存在与不存在"
It's, uh, "Being and Not Being."
我本身喜欢蜷缩在精彩的神秘中
I like to curl up with a juicy mystery meself.
看啊 是埃菲尔铁塔
Oh, look, there's the Eiffel Tower.
好漂亮
Oh, that's lovely.
那里是歌剧院
That's the opera.
我帮你提行李？
May I help you with your luggage?
里面还没东西
Nothing in it yet.
挺特别的 不是吗？
Oh. That's something, innit?
恐怕他姐姐不知道拖把在哪里
I don't think his sister knows where the mop is.
哪里肯定有扫帚和簸箕的
There must be a dustpan and brush somewhere.
噢 你不用动手的 亲爱的
Oh, you don't have to do that, love.
你肯定有更好的事情做
You must have better things to do.
不 并没有
No, not really.
每次走秀结束 都会有种空虚感
After the défilé,there's always a certain feeling of emptiness.
好吧 亲爱的
All right, ducks.
这下有事儿干了
Now we're in business.
这里是怎么了
-哈里斯太太？  -你好 亲爱的
-Mrs. Harris? -Hello, love.
-小姐  -她是个干活儿的好手
-Mademoiselle. -She's a good worker.
要是模特做不成了 我可以给你找到工作 姑娘
I can always find you a job, my girl, if the modeling don't work out.
我真是无法形容的丢脸 让你看到家里...
不 没有
No, no.
我一直没时间...
不 别这么说 没什么的
让我来
-对不起  -不 是我抱歉
不 都怪我 我不该...
哈里斯太太做了晚饭
M-Mrs. Harris has cooked the dinner.
你看起来需要好好吃一顿饭
You look like you could do with a good square meal,
你们俩都是
the pair of you.
娜塔莎小姐有其他的安排
Well, Mademoiselle Natasha has other engagements.
我相信迪奥的门面一向要出席派对 或是首演的
I'm sure the face of Dior is always at a party or premiere.
有个晚宴 晚一点
There's a soiréelater.
来吧 饭好了
Come on. Grub's up.
上菜
Here we are.
不要冷掉啊
Don't let it get cold.
-好胃口  -好胃口
-Bon appétit. -Bon appétit.
我家艾迪最喜欢的
My Eddie's favorite.
要是有肉汁 就更好吃了
Be even better if we had a bit of gravy.
-这道菜叫什么？  -蟾蜍进洞(布丁香肠)
-Um, and what's the dish named? -Toad-in-the-hole.
青蛙在...
在下水道
好多书啊 富维尔先生
What a lot of books, Mr. Fauvel.
娜塔莎有一本好书 讲凶杀谜案的
Natasha's got a corker, a murder-mystery.
是不是 亲爱的？
Don't you, ducks?
“存在与不存在”
你在看萨特的书？
-我们应该说英语  -是 当然
-We should speak English. -Oh, yeah. Of course.
我...我很高兴知道
Um, I-I'm interested to learn
娜塔莎小姐在看一本书
that Mademoiselle Natasha is reading a book
是法国哲学家让·保罗·萨特写的
by the French philosopher JeanPaul Sartre.
作者要我们思考 服务生的情况
The author asks us to consider the case of the waiter.
服务生真的是服务生
Is the waiter the waiter,
还是 只是描述服务生是什么而已？
or is it just an expression of what the waiter is?
类似于 我是真的会计 或这是一种外在印象？
Um, similarly, am I the accountant, or is that an outward impression?
娜塔莎小姐是巴黎
Um, is Mademoiselle Natasha only the most beautiful,
最美丽 最出色的模特 或是...
the most exquisitely divine Parisian model, or...
或是 外表之下另有他人？
Or is there another person behind the facade?
是的
Yes.
哈里斯太太是清洁工 或是 她的存在有更多意义？
Is Mrs. Harris the cleaner, or is there more to define her existence?
对极了
Exactement.
我是来自巴特西的清洁工 多简单
I'm a cleaner from Battersea. No mystery there.
不 你是一个梦想着
Uh, no, you're a cleaner who dreams
全世界最美丽礼服的清洁工
of the most beautiful gown in the world.
噢 做梦 嗯？
Oh, dreams, eh?
天知道薇收到电报后会说什么
God knows what Vi is gonna say when she gets that blooming telegram.
哈里斯太太？
Mrs. Harris?
我姐姐的衣服 你尽管穿
Uh, please help yourself to my sister's clothes.
谢谢 亲爱的 我不用的
Oh, thanks, love. Um, I'm all right.
她肯定坚持的
Uh, she would insist.
晚安
Good night.
晚安 亲爱的
Night, love.
好梦
Sweet dreams.
站直 夫人
Stand straight, madame.
不 但是...
Non, mais...
别动 你干嘛动呢？
Keep still. Why do you move?
抱歉 抱歉
Sorry. Sorry.
卡雷先生？
有一些变化 我需要和你谈谈
是玛格丽特公主要求的
玛格丽特公主？噢 我喜欢她
Princess Margaret? Oh, I like her.
从她眼中可以看到一丝顽皮
You can see a little bit of mischief in her eye.
我们最尊贵的客人 需要我们最为用心
Our distinguished clients demand our utmost discretion.
我们走吧 卡雷先生
今天就到这里
That's all for today.
这人可够难讨好的 不是吗
Little bit of that one goes a long way, don't it?
她有什么不痛快的？
What's eating her?
客人越重要 就越难
Well, the more grand the client, the more difficult.
他们的愿望必须得到满足
Their wishes must be accommodated always,
哪怕是要从头来过
even if it means starting afresh.
而且不交货 他们是不付钱的
And they do not pay until delivery.
如果的话 有太多要花钱的地方
If then. There are so many salaries to find.
布料 穗带 刺绣 纽扣
The fabric, braid, embroidery, buttons
全都必须是最好的
all must be the very best.
每个人都有压力
The pressure is on everyone:
富维尔先生和会计们
on Mr. Fauvel and the accounts,
科尔伯特夫人 还有裁缝们
on Madame Colbert and the seamstresses,
甚至是迪奥先生 一向都扛着很大压力
even on Monsieur Dior himself, always such pressure.
难怪富维尔先生看到我的小手包 那么开心了
Well, no wonder Mr. Fauvel was so pleased to see my little handbag.
事实上 哈里斯夫人
Well, in truth, Madame Harris, all of us fear
我们都很担心迪奥公司无法坚持下去了
the House of Dior cannot keep going this way.
是 先生
Oui, monsieur.
娜塔莎小姐
你好吗 亲爱的？
You all right, love?
醒醒啦
Wakey, wakey.
他们在叫你呢
They're calling for you.
抱歉 我就是累了
Um, I'm sorry. I'm just tired.
你需要放个假
You could do with a little holiday.
已经给我带来益处了
It's doing me the power of good already.
是啊 那可太好了
Yes, that would be nice.
我一个人在海边...
By myself at the seaside,
人哪儿去了？
抱歉 我得走了
I'm sorry. I must go.
谢谢
Thank you.
抱歉
不 不行
谢谢
Thank you.
衣服试得如何 夫人？
How was your fitting, madame?
这不是我的老朋友 玫瑰花先生嘛
Well, if it isn't my old pal, Mr. Rosebud.
很抱歉我们没有正式认识一下
I regret we were not properly introduced.
伊波利特·德·沙萨涅侯爵
Marquis Hypolite de Chassagne.
艾达·哈里斯 巴特西来的寡妇
Harris, widow of Battersea.
这位好朋友是谁啊？
Who's this fine fella?
这是内斯奎克
This is Nesquik.
我相信迪奥先生会满足你心中的愿望？
So, I trust Monsieur Dior fulfills your heart's desire?
他们对我太好了
Oh, they're being ever so kind.
露易斯欧迪 名字我都忘了
Louise Odier. I'd forgotten the name.
噢 我一定要给你看样东西
Oh, I must show you something.
拜托了 不会耽误你很久
Please, I won't detain you long.
跟我说说 你在巴黎过得开心吗？
So, tell me, how are you enjoying your time in Paris?
我太太很喜欢花卉市场
我们几乎到最后都还有来
We came here almost until the end.
已经7年了
It's been seven years now.
我们会改变 但不会遗忘
We mend, but we don't forget.
当你向全世界展示你的迪奥礼服
When you display your Dior dress to the world,
一定会很完美
it will be perfection.
我朋友薇 觉得我疯了
My pal Vi thinks I'm barmy.
"你要那条裙子做什么？"
"What do you want that dress for?
"你什么时候穿呢"
When are you gonna wear it?"
我不怀疑你对这种高质量礼服的渴望
Oh, I do not question your desire for a gown of such quality,
哪怕只是你自己喜欢
even if it is for your eyes alone.
不 不 正相反 我理解
No, no, on the contrary, I understand.
你瞧 这样一朵玫瑰 或是像你那件美丽的礼服
You see, a rose like this one or a beautiful gown such as yours,
它们...它们会唤起
they... they recall the days
当年我们正值青春年华的日子
when we were in the full flower of our youth.
喂 我的青春还没过去呢
Oi, don't write me off just yet.
-万分抱歉  -开玩笑啦
-Oh, a thousand apologies. -Oh, no.
请允许我做出弥补
Please, allow me to make amends.
你今晚有什么安排吗？
Have you any arrangements for tonight?
谢谢
Oh, thank you.
香槟？
Some champagne?
好 谢谢 一点就好
Uh, oh, yes, please. Just a drop.
-谢谢  -你一定要尝尝鱼子酱
-Thank you. -Now, you-you must try the caviar.
好啊
Oh. Right.
-干杯  -干杯
-Cheers. -Cheers.
-不错吧？  -嗯
-Nice, huh? -Mm.
你好
Uh, oh, hello!
这身装扮应该糊弄不了任何人 是不是？
I don't think that getup's gonna fool anyone. Do you?
-可爱的姑娘们  -很快你就会看到有多可爱了
-Lovely girls. Hmm. -Soon, you'll see how lovely.
喔 悠着点儿啊
Ooh! Oh. Steady on.
天啊 姑娘们这钱赚得辛苦
Blimey, they earn their keep, them girls.
起码我做清洁的时候
Well, least when I'm cleaning,
不需要面带微笑 脱衣服
I don't have to smile and strip as well.
晚上好啊 哈里斯太太
Bonsoir, Mrs. Harris.
-娜塔莎 你好啊 亲爱的  -你好
-Natasha. Hello, love. -Hello.
晚上好 小姐
Bonsoir, mademoiselle.
-要和我们一起吗？  -好 谢谢
-Would you like to join us? -Uh, yes, please.
-你和谁一起来的？  -投资商
-Who are you here with, then? -Investors.
我可以逃出来一会儿
I escape but only for a moment.
他们不能从早到晚地让你工作啊
They don't half keep you at it, all day and all night as well.
为了迪奥公馆 这是我的义务
For Maison Dior, this is my obligation.
迪奥不只是礼服
Ah, well, Dior is not just about gowns.
同样也代表着优雅 颓废
It's also about elegance and decadence
以及巴黎的生活品味
and the savoir-vivreof Paris, and...
而你 娜塔莎小姐
and you, Mademoiselle Natasha,
你是迪奥皇冠上的珠宝
you are the jewel of this Dior crown.
我更想待在家里看书
Well, I would prefer to be at home with a book.
你这么说可真逗
It's funny you should say that.
我把富维尔先生一个人丢在家里看书呢
I've left Mr. Fauvel at home reading a book.
那本书叫...
It was called...
"多管闲事"？之类的
"Nosy"? Something like that.
恶心：萨特的小说
-"恶心"？  -不知道诶
与他的萨特和知识分子世界相比
Why does he tolerate the fashion house
他为何要在时尚界忍气吞声呢？
compared to his world of Sartre and the intellect?
我想他有自己的理由吧
Well, I-I think he has his reasons.
你喜欢这表演吗
Do you enjoy the show?
喜欢 最...最后面那个 她...
Yeah, the one... the one at the end, she...
她长得和我提尔达姨妈一模一样
she's a dead ringer for my Aunt Tilda.
从后面看
From behind.
好 真的很开心 但我该走了
Well, this was lovely, but I should go.
-谢谢  -等一下 亲爱的
-Thank you. -Oh, just-just a minute, love.
你的刘海 有点分开了
Your fringe. There's a little gap.
好了
That's it.
-有人被你征服了呀  -胡说八道
-You have made a conquest. -Oh, get away with you.
你大胆追求自己的梦想 哈里斯太太
You dare to follow your dreams, Mrs. Harris.
好样的
Bravo.
拜拜 亲爱的
Bye, love.
-晚安  -晚安 娜塔莎
-Bonsoir. -Bonsoir, Natasha.
-再加点香槟？  -一点就好
-Some more champagne? -Oh, just a drop.
我9点半试衣服
I've got me fitting at- 30.
天啊
Oh, God!
老天啊
Oh, Gordon Bennett!
当心！
Careful!
蠢货！
白痴！让开！
滚蛋！滚蛋！阿瓦隆滚蛋！
难以置信
I can't believe this.
阿瓦隆 你这头臭猪！
把他塞进垃圾箱！
抱歉！
Sorry!
抱歉 对不起
Sorry. Sorry.
-我很抱歉  -不 不 不
-I'm so sorry. -No, no, no.
这不可能 完全不可能
This is not possible, not at all.
不不不 拜托 我...我从来不迟到的 我...
No, no, no, please, I-I'm... I'm never late. I...
真的 我不会的 我从来不迟到 抱歉
R-Really, I'm not. I'm never late. Sorry.
你要求我们"快快快"可你却根本不重视
You demand of us, "Vite, vite, vite," but you have no respect.
不 这不可能
No, this cannot be done.
根本不可能
Not at all.
现在我走了 结束了
Now I depart. This is finished.
不不不不 别这样 拜托 求你了 卡雷先生
No, no, no, no. Please, please, p-please, Mr. Carré.
科尔伯特夫人 拜托了
Madame Colbert, please.
卡雷先生不肯继续了
Monsieur Carré refuses to proceed.
我能做什么？
What can I do?
不 不 当然 我...不 我理解的
No. No, of course, I...
No, I understand.
是的 我当然理解 真的
Yeah, of course I do. I do.
迪奥 不只是...一件礼服
Dior, it's-it's not just a gown.
是...
It's, um...
是优雅 是...是精明 是所有的
It's all the elegance and-and the savvy and all that.
我知道的
I-I know that.
我会想办法看看怎么退你押金的
I will see what can be done to return your deposit.
不 我不...
No, I don't...
那 卡雷先生...
我...
I-I...
我不要...我不要押金
I don't want... I don't want me deposit.
我真是个蠢货 不是吗？
Right Champagne Charlie, aren't I?
狠狠教训了我 享受高档生活
Serves me right, living the high life.
我很尊重你们 你们每一位
I do respect you, all of you.
不重要了
Never mind, eh?
谢谢 亲爱的 你一直对我特别好
Thanks, love. You've been ever so kind.
哈里斯太太 你走之前
Madame Harris, would you care to see the atelier
愿意参观一下工作室吗？
before you leave?
-你们好 女士们  -你好
-Bonjour, mesdames. -Bonjour.
这间是裁剪室
So, this room is for cutting.
-你好  -早上好
-Bonjour. -Morning.
结构设计
Structure du couture.
非结构设计
Unstructured couture.
珠饰
Passementerie.
羽毛
Plumassier.
刺绣
Broderie.
哈里斯夫人？
你还好吗？
这不是缝纫
It's not sewing.
是在造月光
It's making moonlight.
我是上天堂了吗？
Have I gone to heaven?
哈里斯太太问她是不是上天堂了
女士们！
赶紧地 接着干活儿！
迪奥先生
你看这块布料适合给阿芙罗狄蒂吗？
可以 我喜欢这颜色
-我拿给卡雷先生看?  -好的
卡雷先生 这块布料要更华贵
或许我们可以用来...？
我们找到了共同点 这只小麻雀和我
We have found some common ground, the little sparrow and I.
她是很有能力的裁缝 科尔伯特夫人
缝扣子能出什么差错呢？
十年来 我日以继夜都站在
I have stood at Monsieur Dior's shoulder
迪奥先生的肩膀上
day and night for ten years,
自从大师推出他的第一个系列
since le maîtreunveiled his first collection.
全世界最时髦的女人都来到了蒙田大道
The most fashionable women in the world come to the Avenue Montaigne.
皇室 妓女 高矮胖瘦 老幼美丑
Royalty and courtesans, thin, fat, young, old, ugly,
或是某种那什么什么
or with a certain je ne sais quoi.
但后来出现了你 哈里斯太太
But then there is you, Mrs. Harris.
当女主管这么多年
All my time as directress,
我从没遇到过你这样的人
I have never encountered anyone like you.
在我的生活中 会遇到各种各样的人
In my walk of life, you meet all sorts.
作为一个好老板 我必须让工人们开心
As a good boss, I must keep my workers happy,
而他们的心愿 是完成你的裙子
and their wish is to complete your dress.
衷心感谢
Oh. Much obliged.
所以你愿意好心回答我的问题吗？
So you will do me the courtesy of answering my questions, no?
好
Yeah.
干杯！
干杯
Cheers!
你为什么来这儿呢 哈里斯太太？
Why do you come here, Mrs. Harris?
显然 昂贵的 有名的 必定被注视 欣赏 复制
EÉvidemment, the rich and titled must be seen, admired, copied.
但是 你如此渴望的这件迪奥礼服
But this Dior dress that you desire so much,
你要去哪里穿呢？
where will you wear it?
是维也纳歌剧院舞会 还是夏洛特皇后的舞会？
At the Vienna Opera Ball or Queen Charlotte's?
你是会穿去高级的地方
Will you wear it to polish floors,
还是就一直挂在你的衣柜里呢？
or will you keep it shut in your little wardrobe?
迪奥礼服设计出来 就是要惊艳 要赏心悦目的
A Dior dress is designed to astonish and delight.
你要如何做到呢 哈里斯太太？
How will you do that, Mrs. Harris?
你...
You...
原谅我如此直白 但你谁都不是 无名小卒
Forgive me for saying this, but you are nobody, invisible.
你如何赋予这件礼服 它应有的生命呢？
How will you give this dress the life it deserves?
这是我的梦想
It's my dream.
我的钱也和别人的没区别
And my money's as good as anybody else's.
当然 没错
Bien sûr. Hmm.
你或许可以买你的梦想 但你拿来做什么呢？
You may buy your dream, but what will you do with it?
是 进来
Oui, entrez.
哈里斯夫人 这是给你的
Mrs. Harris, these are for you.
来自侯爵先生
From Monsieur le Marquis.
他想约你明天喝茶
He wishes that you visit for tea tomorrow.
沙萨涅侯爵？
Le Marquis de Chassagne?
可是...他谁都不见的啊
But... he receives nobody.
但我谁也不是 不是吗？
But I am nobody, aren't I?
我从没想过迪奥这样的地方 会出问题
I never thought a place like Dior would have problems.
我看到那件礼服 想到了梦和童话故事
I saw that dress, and I thought of dreams and fairy tales.
是啊 我们就像一个童话故事
Yes, we are like a fairy tale.
美好 但不真实
Lovely but not real.
如今还有地方留给梦想吗？
Is there a place for that today?
我们都需要有梦想
Oh, we need our dreams.
尤其是现在
Now more than ever.
如果你可以拥有这个 干嘛还要迪奥呢？
If you can have this, why do you need Dior?
高级时装对我们 和我们的客人 是一种虚荣
Haute couture is a vanity for us and our clients.
事实上 我不认为迪奥公司能够坚持下去
In truth, I don't think the House of Dior can survive.
不 亲爱的 那可是太悲哀了
No, love, that would be a tragedy.
你不能让那种事发生
You can't allow that to happen.
我有个主意
Well, I have an idea,
但需要一种新的思维方式
but it requires a new way of thinking.
什么？被专横阻碍了？
What? Bossy Boots in the way?
科尔伯特夫人 她守卫着圣殿
Madame Colbert, she guards the temple.
她让一个清洁大婶买下迪奥礼服
She let a cleaning lady buy a Dior gown.
-钱话事  -对 而你听得懂
-Money talks. -Yes, and you know what it says,
所以你必须为此做点什么
so you have to do something about it.
我知道你可以的 你这么聪明
I know you can. You're ever so clever.
只有你相信
You're the only one who believes.
这里是怎么回事？
What's going on here?
像是首映礼
It looks like a premiere.
好激动啊
Oh, exciting.
那个是让·法布尔 电影明星
Oh, that's Jean Fabre, the movie star.
嗯 他自己也知道
Mm, and don't he know it?
是娜塔莎！
Oh, it's Natasha! Oh!
-娜塔莎！  -你在干什么？不 不行
-Natasha! Ooh-ooh! -What are you doing? No, no.
-娜塔莎！  -不
-Natasha! -No.
你好
Hello.
-晚上好 哈里斯太太  -你很漂亮
-Good evening, Mrs. Harris. -You look lovely.
谢谢 晚上好 富维尔先生
Thank you. Bonsoir, Monsieur Fauvel.
晚上好 我们不知道你...
Bonsoir.Um, we didn't know you were, uh...
我们只是路过
We were just passing.
你们俩今晚有什么安排？
So, what are you two doing this evening?
-这个...  -娜塔莎
-Oh, well... Oh. -Natasha.
抱歉 我必须走了
I'm sorry. I-I must go.
-见到你们很高兴  -是啊 拜拜 亲爱的
-It was great to see you. -Oh, yeah. Ta-ta, love.
我想只是作秀而已
I think it's just for show.
我看他不像是结婚的对象
I'm not sure that he's the marrying kind.
哈里斯太太 我求你 你...你别再撮合我们了
Mrs. Harris, I-I beg of you, you-you need to stop this coupling thing
不然我要死于羞辱了
before I die of humiliation...
拜托 够了！
Please. Enough!
好吧 我不聋
All right. I'm not deaf.
我当然爱娜塔莎 谁不爱啊？
Of course I'm in love with Natasha. I mean, who isn't?
抱歉 可人生不只是月光和电影
I'm sorry, but life is not all moonlight and movies.
为什么不能是？
Why can't it be?
我一个人生活了太久 都不想过了
I've spent too long on my own, wishing my life away.
你不想跟我一样的
You don't want to do the same thing.
哈里斯太太 我认为你的浪漫梦想 非常适合巴黎
Mrs. Harris, I think your dreams of romance fit Paris very well.
请原谅 但或许渴望爱情的人 是你
Forgive me, but perhaps it is you who wishes to be in love.
你必须遵循你的内心
You who must attend to your own heart.
拜托 艾迪 说句话吧 亲爱的
Come on, Eddie, say something, love.
让我理解这一切 因为我做不到
Try and make some sense of this, 'cause I can't.
这都是你的指引
This is all your doing.
想方设法 让你女人跑到巴黎
Coming up with the readies to get your girl to Paris.
巴黎
Paris.
为了认识某个人？
To meet someone?
请吧？
Shall we?
迪奥的姑娘们说 我的裙子快完成了
The girls at Dior say my dress is almost finished.
是啊 或许就是明天
Yeah. Maybe tomorrow.
然后我就...我就要回家了
And then I'll be... I'll be back off home.
是啊 很愉快
Yeah, it's lovely.
真的 真的很愉快
Really, really lovely.
垃圾夫人特有的欢迎方式
That rubbish lady's welcome to hers.
其实挺讽刺的
And here's the irony.
迪奥先生为美丽的女人创作精美的诗歌
Monsieur Dior makes exquisite poems for beautiful women
以庆祝她们的活力和完美
in celebration of their freshness and perfection
却只看到它们被老太婆夺走
only to see them carried away by old frumps.
好比那位讨厌的阿瓦隆夫人
Like that dreadful Madame Avallon.
是啊
Oh, yeah.
然而呢 当然 还有那些保留着...
Whereas, of course, there are those who retain
某种特别的那什么什么
a certain je ne sais quoi,
一种难以言喻的魅力
an indefinable allure.
请允许我为你呈上一壶英国茶
Allow me to present to you a pot of English tea.
噢 来得正好
Oh, just the job.
谢谢 玛利亚
Hmm. Merci, Maria.
现在我们让茶泡一会儿
And now we let the pot brew.
-是这么说吗？  -没错
-Is that the correct form, yes? -That's the ticket.
我得给你织个茶壶套
I'll have to knit you a tea cozy.
是啊 出于我一直不清楚的原因
Yes, for reasons that were never clear to me,
我6岁就被送去温莎的寄宿学校了
I was sent as a boy of six to a boarding school in Windsor,
在那里培养了我对茶和所有英国事物的兴趣
and that's where I acquired a taste for tea and of all things English.
等的这会儿 我有样东西想给你看
While we wait, there's something I would like you to see.
跟我来
Come with me.
这个
There.
才6岁 可怜的小家伙
Six years old, you poor mite.
家里也没多好
Well, home was not much better.
不过是 我受了不少罪
But yes, I suffered.
我那时很弱小 成天被欺负
I was a weak little boy, perpetually bullied.
知道吗 看到你的一刻
You know, as soon as I saw you,
心里就有种共鸣
I felt this connection in my heart.
我也说不好 或许
I don't know, perhaps...
你的笑容 你的善良 你的...
your smile, your kindness, your...
你的英式幽默
your English humor.
我就知道你让我想到了某人
I knew you reminded me of someone,
一个对我很重要的人 可是谁呢？
someone very dear to me, but who?
就在昨天 我绞尽脑汁回想
And only yesterday, as I searched my memories,
想到一个曾经照顾过我的人
did I realize there was a person who took care of me.
她的生活就是不知疲倦的苦差
Her life was one of tireless drudgery,
可她却能抽出时间安慰我 抹去我的眼泪
and yet she found the time to comfort me and dry my tears.
她的名字是 麦多克斯夫人
Her name was Mrs. Maddox,
但我们都叫她"拖把太太"
but we used to call her Mrs. Mops.
就是她
There.
我...我让你想到了"拖把太太"？
I-I remind you of Mrs. Mops?
-是的  -清洁工？
-Ah, yes. -The cleaner?
"拖把太太"擦干我的眼泪 让我恢复了笑容
Mrs. Mops dried my tears and made me smile again,
就和过去这几天的你一样 哈里斯太太
as you have, Mrs. Harris, these past few days.
我真希望我的戴尔芬能认识你
I do wish my Delphine could have known you.
你瞧 你给予需要的人以安慰
You see, you give comfort to those in need
却不求任何回报
without asking anything in return.
是这样吗？
Is that right?
你是这样看我的？
Is that how you see me?
明白我们之间为何会产生共鸣了吧？
You see why there is a connection between us?
来 我们去享受一杯美味的英国茶 好吗？
Now, let's have a nice cup of English tea, shall we?
不了 谢谢
Uh, no, thank you.
我还是走吧
I'd best be getting along.
他们在沙龙等我
They're expecting me at the salon.
阿瓦隆 黑心老板！
阿瓦隆 进垃圾桶！
我们要让你烂掉 阿瓦隆！
玛格丽特？
Marguerite?
怎么了？
What's the matter?
进来吧
In you go.
你为什么辞退这些姑娘啊？
What's this about you letting all these girls go?
没事吧 亲爱的？
Ooh. You all right, love?
没必要让她们和你一样免费打工吧
It would not be necessary if they worked for free, as you do.
她们需要工作 都要养家糊囗呢
They need their jobs. They've got families to feed.
失陪
Excusez-moi.
是 是很令人难过 但与你无关
Yes, it is very sad, but this is not of your concern.
那咱们走着瞧
Well, we'll see about that.
拜托 夫人 你已经插手了这里的所有事
Please, madame, you have reached into every corner of this establishment.
我坚持请你尊重我们的隐私
Now, I insist that you respect our privacy.
-你去哪儿 哈里斯太太？  -去见老板
-Where are you going, Mrs. Harris? -To see the boss.
-你不能 不行  -来吧 姑娘们
-You cannot. No. -Come on, girls.
-拜托 不要  -跟我来 快快快
-Please. No. -Follow me. Vite, vite.
我们走 姑娘们 都来
Here we go, girls. Come on.
放下工具
Down tools.
都来 跟在我后面一起来
Come on, get behind me. Join us.
是的 今天有很重要的工作
Yeah, got a really important job today.
-噢 真漂亮 不过跟我来  -哈里斯太太
-Ooh, you look lovely, but come on. -Mrs. Harris!
-都来帮我  -哈里斯太太！
-Come and do this for me. -Mrs. Harris!
你必须马上停止
You must stop this at once.
你不知道自己在做什么
You have no idea what you are doing.
不 我知道 这叫罢工
Oh, yes, I do. It's called a strike.
求你了
好了 女士们 来吧
Right, ladies, come on.
跟我来 没时间了 亲爱的
Follow me. No time for that, dear.
喂！没必要推搡 都来啊
Oi! No need to push and shove. Come on.
待着别动！
玛格丽特 你是疯了吗？
你给我站住！
起身 安德烈 要干活儿了
On your feet, André. There's work to be done.
这都怪你 富维尔先生 做点什么啊
你觉得我能阻止这个女人吗？
逮捕她！
我是共产主义者 夫人 我支持她
让我过去！
哈里斯太太 我求你 不要这样
Mrs. Harris, I beg of you, do not do this.
这是你的机会 安德烈
This is your chance, André, and how many chances
-你这辈子遇到过多少次机会？  -不 听我说...
-do you get in your lifetime? -No, look...
迪奥先生 占用你10分钟 谢谢
Monsieur Dior, ten minutes of your time, please.
足够富维尔先生拯救这家公司了
That's all Mr. Fauvel needs to save the company.
我？我要怎么...
Me? What do I-I...
迪奥先生 我很抱歉
说吧 亲爱的 你可以的 告诉他你的计划
Go on, pet. You can do it. Tell him your plan.
说啊
Go on.
一个缺少优雅的世界
失去了卓越 没有了迪奥
不 那不可能
可如何能让迪奥公司度过眼下的难关呢？
与其让全世界来到蒙田大道
Rather than the world coming to Avenue Montaigne,
迪奥必须走向世界
Dior must go out to the world
为所有人提供商品
with a range of goods available to all.
香水 长袜 奢侈品
Uh, perfume, stockings, luxury that...
让普通女人也买得起
that the ordinary woman can afford.
那样就不是迪奥公司了
也不再是高级时装了
我们的名声就是建立在独一无二之上的
你等一下 露露
是
Oui.
富维尔先生 给你十分钟
怎么了？
What?
噢 好的
Oh, right.
好运 亲爱的
Good luck, love.
还有你
谢谢
Merci.
我们罢工胜利了！
阿瓦隆进监狱！
为工人们欢呼！
十年前 迪奥公司展出子第一个系列
独一无二是关键 没错
但今天 有一位崭新的女性
But today, there's a new woman,
一位当代女性 她知道自己要什么
a modern woman who knows what she wants
并且她需要能够购买
and needs to be able to buy it.
今天 我们遇到了哈里斯太太
Today, there's Mrs. Harris.
老板同意了我们的计划 就意味着...
The maître'sagreement to our plan means that,
远不是失去工作 而是需要更多
far from losing jobs, we will need more.
更多 更多的工作
Many, many more.
好极了！
Bravo!
你确定是这条街吗？
Are you sure this is the right street?
肯定是 每个月支票都是寄到这里的
Must be. This is where I send her check every month.
里面不会有一粒灰尘
There won't be a speck of dust inside.
这你可以肯定
You can bet your life.
就是这儿
This is it.
不
No.
-别来烦我  -就聊几句
-Leave me in peace. -Just a word.
为什么？我认输
Why? I concede.
你们赢了 哈里斯太太
The victory is yours, Mrs. Harris.
科尔伯特夫人 我恳求你
是谁啊？
没事的 别担心 我马上就来
他们干什么啊？
放心吧
我丈夫在战争中受了伤
My husband-he was damaged in the war.
需要时常有人照顾
He requires constant care.
不是你做 就得雇人做
Which you either do or pay for.
难怪你在人前是那个样子了
No wonder you got all that front on you.
有话请直说吧
Say what you want, please.
夫人 我很抱歉冒犯了你
Madame, I'm so sorry to have offended you.
我非常敬重你
I hold you in the highest regard, and it was
从没想过强迫改变...
never my intention to force a change on...
你描述的未来非常合理
The future you describe makes perfect sense,
但我不想参与
but I want no part of it.
别这样 拜托了
Uh, no, please.
你千万不能考虑离开啊
You must not think of leaving.
或许我在这个位置坐了太久
Perhaps I have been too long in my post,
做伟大男人背后 默默付出的女人 做了太久
too long the invisible woman behind the great man.
宣战言论啊 加油 姐们儿
Fighting talk. You go, girl.
我不像你一样喜欢革新 哈里斯太太
I'm not a revolutionary like you, Mrs. Harris.
我只希望不被打扰
I simply wish to be left alone.
嗯 这...这没问题 很好啊
Well, that's... that's all fine and dandy,
天知道这也是你应得的
and Lord knows you deserve it,
但你知道 没了你 天就塌了 不是吗
but you know it'll fall apart without you, don't you?
相信我 我见过太多了
Trust me, I've seen it over and over.
女人选择离开后 男人连10分钟都活不下去
When the lady ups and leaves, the gent don't last ten minutes.
你是被需要的
You're needed.
尤其是现在
Now more than ever.
不然谁来让公司平稳运作啊？
Who else is gonna keep things up to scratch?
安德烈或是迪奥先生可都不行
Not André or Monsieur Dior.
两个男人懂什么啊
What would two men know about that?
你和我 知道吗 咱俩很像的
You and me, you know, we're two peas in a pod.
我们给别人收拾烂摊子 让花园里一片美好
We clean up everybody's mess and make everything in the garden lovely.
我们是他们依靠的人
We're the ones they rely on.
他们都不知道我们的能耐
They don't even know what we do,
但不必怀疑 少了咱 全都得乱套
but as sure as eggs is eggs, without us, it all goes tits up.
或许是要和大师谈谈了
Perhaps a conversation with le maîtreis required.
或许吧
Perhaps.
明天 你要告诉娜塔莎你的感情
And tomorrow, you tell Natasha how you feel.
可娜塔莎小姐离开了迪奥
Oh, but Mademoiselle Natasha has left Dior.
她要离开巴黎了
She's leaving Paris.
和你一样 哈里斯夫人 她也想去追梦
Like you, Mrs. Harris, she wishes to follow her dream.
继续找 亲爱的 她肯定就在这儿的
Keep looking, love. She's got to be here somewhere.
她走了 这样最好
She's gone. It's for the best.
你要是不好好找...等下我就
You're gonna get yourself
狠狠揪你耳朵
a good clip round the ear in a minute if you don't...
等一下
Hang on.
等一下 我知道了
Hang on a minute. I know.
这边
Here.
迪奥夫人啊
Oh. Madame Dior.
-这么漂亮  -你也不赖啊
-Magnifique. -Oh, well, not so bad yourself.
我们在找一个女孩儿
Uh, we're looking for a girl.
她...她有点不开心
Um, she's... she's a bit upset.
是你见过最聪慧 最可爱的女人
是迪奥的模特
She's a Dior model.
是那个吗？
-娜塔莎  -娜塔莎
-Oh, Natasha. -Natasha.
出什么事了？
这种生活 不适合我
This life, it's-it's not for me.
对 当然不适合
No, of course it isn't.
站在一个底座上 像漂亮的娃娃一样被展示
Stuck on a pedestal, paraded around like a beautiful doll.
任何人都能看出 这个女孩并不喜欢
Anyone can see the girl doesn't want it.
哈里斯太太说得对 那不是我
Mrs. Harris is right. It's not who I am.
萨特会说 你会发现自己夹在
As Sartre would say, y-you find yourself conflicted
"自在存在"与"自为存在"之间左右为难
between être-en-soi et être-pour-soi.
在"自为"和"自在"间
Between "for itself" and "in itself."
"自在"是人类生活中
EÊtre-en-soibeing those aspects of human life
包括意识的各种方面
that involves consciousness,
而自然事实就是"自为"
whereas physical facts are être-pour-soi.
存在主义者
那样的话 事物就不会是本该有的样子
In which case, things would be what they are not.
没错
Exactement.
事物不是本有的样子 也不是它们不是的样子
Things are what they are not, and they're not what they're not.
安德烈 老天啊 快吻她
André, for God's sake, just kiss her.
是的 拜托 快吻我
Yes. For God's sake, just kiss me.
和我一起留在巴黎吧 娜塔莎
可我已经跟迪奥先生说过了
你还可以学哲学啊
让无形变有形
你没有在巴黎找到爱吗 迪奥夫人？
You did not find love in Paris, Madame Dior?
没 没有
Oh, no. No.
我本以为太迟了 但...
I thought it was too late, but...
现在我说不准了
...now I'm not so sure.
-你好 亲爱的  -你好 艾达
-Hello, love. -Hello, Ada.
好啦 来啦
Oh. All right, all right.
我的老天
Gordon Bennett.
好啦
All right.
-你好 亲爱的 快进来  -感谢上帝你回来了
-Oh, hello, love. Come in. -Oh, thank God you're back.
也没多久 要不要喝杯茶？
Oh, well, not long. Do you want a cuppa?
没时间了
No time.
-我急啊  -好吧
-This is an emergency. -Oh. Right.
好 深呼吸 告诉我发生了什么
Okay, well, deep breath and tell me what's up.
我不能去 但我要是不去...
I can't go, but if I don't...
留下好印象 真的太重要了 是不是？
Oh, it's so important to make a good impression, you know?
是啊 你想打动谁呢？
I do. Who you trying to impress?
康格尔德先生 制片人
Mr. Korngold, the producer.
我要和他一起去皇家咖啡厅 参加盛大的晚宴
I'm to partner him to the big dinner at the Café Royal.
到时候大家都会去
Everybody will be there.
这是难得的机会 可是你看
It's a priceless opportunity. But look.
是啊 是有点...有点皱巴巴的
Oh, well, yeah, it's a bit... it's a bit crumpled,
但是很快就可以熨好的 亲爱的
but we can steam that out in a jiffy, love.
-别担心呢  -不是 你看
-Don't you worry. -No, look.
天啊 是啊 这可是得好好浸泡一下才能洗掉
Oh, dear. Yeah, that's not gonna come out without a good, long soak.
恐怕缎料不能这么洗
I'm not sure the satin's gonna like that.
你不是还有一件吗？那件漂亮的蓝色礼服呢？
Ain't you got another one? What about that lovely blue dress?
送去洗了
It's at the cleaner's.
天啊
Oh, my God.
我要死了
I'm going to die.
好了 打起精神来 够了
All right. Come on, now. That's enough.
-没人想听这种话  -可你不明白啊
-Nobody wants to hear that. -But you don't understand.
基本上康格尔德先生捧的女孩子 都会成为明星
Nearly all Mr. Korngold's girls become stars.
这是我让自己脱颖而出 终于被人看到的机会啊
It's my chance to lift myself out of the rut and be seen at last.
被人看到不等于一切 亲爱的
Well, being seen isn't everything, love.
对我就是啊
It is for me.
来 站起来
Come on. Stand up.
今天是你的幸运日
It's your lucky day.
什么？
What?
为什么？
Why?
-因为我想我可以帮你  -你刚说不行的
-'Cause I think I can help you. -You just said you couldn't.
你要是不起来 那我是没辙
I can't do anything if you don't get up.
好
Right.
衣服脱了 你可以借穿我的礼服
Take off your clothes. You can borrow my dress.
别说傻话了
Don't be ridiculous.
照我说的做 别给我胡闹了
Just do as I say, and a bit less of your nonsense.
去吧 就在屏风后面
Go on, behind the screen.
哈里斯太太？
Mrs. Harris?
你很漂亮 亲爱的
You look lovely, ducks.
正好
Just the ticket.
你的旅途愉快吗？我都忘了问
How was your trip? I should've asked.
你去了哪里？
Where did you go?
-巴黎是啊...  -你说只去一天的
-Paris. Yeah, it was... -You said you'd only be gone a day.
-没有你全都乱套了  -很神奇
-Everything went to pieces without you. -It was magical.
你知道我平时有多整洁的
I mean, you know how tidy I am-normally.
好浪漫
So romantic.
H太太 真人不露相啊你
Mrs. H. You dark horse.
天啊 他来了
Oh, God. That's him.
所以他知道来哪里接你？
Oh. He knew where to come, then?
我就知道你会救我的 亲爱的
I knew you'd rescue me, darling.
你是我的神仙教母呀
You're my fairy godmother.
你好
Hello.
彭罗斯小姐？
Miss Penrose?
亲爱的H太太
Dear Mrs. H,
礼服的事很抱歉 但请不要担心
Sorry about the dress, but please don't worry.
我没事
I'm okay.
我正对着镜子检查我的口红
I was checking my lipstick in the mirror
突然 我就着火了
when suddenly I went up in flames.
如果不是朋友及时相救
I might have burnt to a crisp
我可能就烧成灰了
if a helpful friend hadn't come to my rescue.
康格尔德先生说我应该起诉
Mr. Korngold says I should sue.
我去妈妈家疗伤了
Gone to my mum's to recover.
艾达？
Ada?
你在吗？
You there?
在
Yeah.
抱歉 薇
Sorry, Vi.
你不想活了吗 女人？
You give up the ghost, woman?
你想吓死我们吗？
You want to scare us to death?
还好吗 阿奇？
Oh, all right, Archie?
抱歉弄坏了你的门
Uh, sorry about your door.
她...完全是好意
Uh, she was, um...
我去给你找玻璃来 好吗？
I'll get some glass, yeah?
-修理好  -谢谢
-Fix it up good as new. -Thank you.
什么都不必说
Well, there's no need to say a word.
你出名了
You're famous.
起码你用一切换来的那件礼服是出名了
At least the dress you gave up everything to go and get is.
为什么要送给那个坏丫头啊
Why you give it to that no-good girl, eh?
你心太软了 这是事实
You're too soft, and that's the truth.
礼服必须被看到
It had to be seen.
这样才对
It's only right.
薇
Oh, Vi.
我根本没机会穿的
I never got to wear it.
一次都不可能
Not even once.
艾达 我亲爱的
Oh, Ada, my darling.
我很遗憾
I'm so sorry, eh?
我们不需要华丽的礼服
We don't need no fancy dresses.
我们要去军团舞会上跳他个翻天覆地
We'll go shake our tail feather down at the Legion Dance,
他们都会注视着我们
and they'll all be looking at us.
早上好 纽康比先生
Oh, morning, Mr. Newcombe.
假日过得开心吗 哈里斯太太？
Enjoy your holiday, Mrs. Harris?
非常 谢谢
Very much, thank you.
想念你收拾的屋子呢
Missed your touch about the place.
你还好吗？
Are you quite all right?
今天有点不是我自己
Not quite meself today.
都不知道是谁
Not sure who that is, even.
有点生存危机了
Bit of an existential crisis.
巴黎是会带来这种影响的 振作起来 H太太
Paris will do that to you. Chin up, Mrs. H.
革命要到来了
The revolution is coming.
你看到有个女孩儿穿着迪奥礼服 把自己烧着了吗？
Did you read about the girl who set fire to herself in a Dior gown?
我想就是为了博眼球吧
Ghastly publicity stunt, I suppose.
真是浪费
What a waste.
请你接受我的通知 好吗 丹特夫人
Will you please accept my notice, Lady Dant?
我将要求您在本周末前 把全部的
I will require full and final settlement of your account
-最后的薪水都结算给我  -你不能不管我啊
-by the end of the week. -You can't leave me.
你蔑视他人的存在 还指望忠诚回报
Them days are over when you can treat people like scum
那种日子结束了
and expect loyalty in return.
是的 日安 夫人
Yeah. Good day, milady.
来
There you go.
很快就会好起来了
Be right as rain in no time.
那是谁啊？
Who's that, then?
艾达·哈里斯太太？
Mrs. Harris?
请在这里签字
Sign here, please.
-谢谢  -稍等 还有
-Thank you. -Just a mo'. There's more.
还有？
More?
你确定？不是我生日啊
Are you sure? It's not me birthday.
你是艾达·哈里斯？
You are Harris?
这我都拿不准了
Well, not sure about that, either.
亲爱的哈里斯夫人
Chère Madame Harris,
希望你回到伦敦一切安好
We hope your return journey to London was pleasant,
但在报纸上看到的照片 令我们感到担忧
but we were troubled by a photo we saw in the social pages.
我们立刻就意识到
We knew immediately that once again
你又大发善心了
you had been too kind.
你们搞错了 住手！
听我说 搞错了
一直在剥削工人
was stealing from his workers.
自从他的财产被没收
Since his assets were seized,
阿瓦隆夫人就没能来最后试装
Madame Avallon failed to attend her final fitting
或是为她的礼服买单
or settle the bill for her dress.
八十五
很快就为你改好了衣服
and were quickly able to alter it for you.
如果需要最后的调试
If it needs any final adjustments,
我们知道你的手艺是没问题的
we know you have the skill to do these yourself.
迪奥办公室 请讲
我们都认同 这是我们最起码可以做的
We all agreed it was the least we could do.
宣传带来了订单的暴增
The publicity has resulted in a great increase in orders.
麻烦你帮我包起来？
你一定一下就能认出这花
You will no doubt recognize these blooms
是玛格丽特公主的最爱
as Princess Margaret's Delight.
希望你喜欢这些花
We hope you enjoy the flowers
并保管好你的新礼服
and that you will keep your new dress
远离明火
well away from naked flames.
我们满怀爱意 和最诚挚的感谢
We send it to you with all our love
将它送给你
and our very warmest thanks.
来自克里斯汀
From Christian
以及迪奥公司你所有的朋友们
and all your friends at the House of Dior.
见到你很高兴
G-Good to see you.
-等下见  -好
-See you later. -All right.
给 亲爱的
There you go, love.
干了这杯
Get that down you.
-千杯  -干杯
-Cheers. -Cheers.
谢谢你 薇
Thank you, Vi.
艾达
Oh, Ada.
你好吗 阿奇？
You all right, Archie?
从没这么好过
Never better.
抱歉
S-Sorry.
我就是...
I just...
怎么了？
What?
你似乎有些不同
You seem different.
这是高级时装 知道吗？
Well, it's haute couture, you know?
是吗？
Is it, now?
知道吗？
Know what?
和这裙子无关 我是说 是很漂亮
It's not the frock. I mean, it's lovely and all,
可是...
but, uh...
不 是你
no, it's you.
你...
You...
你很美
You're just beautiful.
谢谢 阿奇
Thank you, Archie.
你真好
That's very nice of you.
不 你一直都很美 从内到外
No, I mean, you've always been beautiful. Inside and out.
只是 有点什么...
Just, there's something...
我也说不清 就像是 一个新的火花 还是什么
I don't know, like, a new spark or something.
-一个"那什么"？  -对极了
-A je ne sais quoi? -That'll be the fella.
我欠你一支舞 不是吗？
I owe you a dance, don't I?
我想是的
I think you do.
我想要认领这支舞
I'd like to claim that dance
和全场最美的姑娘
with the loveliest girl in the room.
今天是你的幸运日
It's your lucky day.
好吧
All right.
希望在等待每个人啊
There is hope for us all.